http://www.nzwine.com/en/privacy-policy/

Visit Us
From cellar doors, winery restaurants, bike trails to boutique vineyard accommodation, discover something new in a New Zealand wine region.
Our Regions
New Zealand's distinctive winegrowing regions each have unique soils and climatic conditions that are expressed in the wines produced.
Our Winestyles
Our temperate maritime climate allows a wide range of wine varieties to flourish. Whatever your preferences, we’re sure to have a wine to suit your palate.
Back
Our Winestyles
Sauvignon Blanc
Chardonnay
Pinot Gris
Riesling
Gewurztraminer
Sparkling
Sustainability
Dig a little deeper into how our winemakers and grape growers are helping their natural environment, local businesses and communities to thrive.
Back
Sustainability
Focus Areas
Sustainable Winegrowing NZ
Organic Winegrowing
Biosecurity
Sustainability in Action
Sustainability Report
Events
Browse our calendar of world-wide events where you can taste New Zealand wine and meet the personalities behind the brands.
Back
Events
Go You! Workshops
New Zealand Wine Week
Photo Gallery
Pinot Noir NZ
The New Zealand Wine Diaries
Marlborough climate and mechanical shaking seminar
Public
New Zealand Wine Week
Public
Pinot Noir Day Quiz
Initiatives
Initiatives
New Zealand’s wine industry is one of the youngest in the world, but the 'can-do' attitude of our pioneering winemakers and growers put in place a solid base for our innovative, world-class industry to flourish.
Back
Initiatives
Bragato Research Institute
Women in Wine
NZW Mentoring Programme
NZ Young Winemaker
NZ Young Viticulturist of the Year
Tomorrow Project & Cheers!
NZ Lighter Wines
Go You! Workshops
Public
Bragato Research Institute
Public
New Zealand Young Winemaker
News & Media
News & Media
Keep up-to-date with our latest press releases, reports and statistics, flick through image and video galleries, and connect with us socially.
Back
News & Media
Our People, Our Stories
Press Releases
Image Galleries
Resources
Statistics & Reports
NZ Winegrower Magazine
Why your privacy matters to us
Here at New Zealand Winegrowers (NZW), our vision is that around the world, New Zealand is renowned for our exceptional wines.  Underpinning that vision is our mission to create enduring value for our members, and everything we do at NZW is directed at achieving our core purpose of protecting and enhancing the reputation of New Zealand wine and supporting the sustainable diversified value growth of New Zealand wine.
We consider integrity to be one of our core values, and our reputation to be our key asset.  We understand that in part this reputation depends on the respectful and responsible management of the personal information we process.  This means that when we process (collect, use, store or share) personal information, we’re committed to doing so in ways that maintain and grow that reputation.
What this privacy statement does
This privacy statement provides an overview of the way we process (collect, use, store and share) personal information. We might also give you more specific information about how we will process your personal information at the time we collect personal information from you.  Although we are primarily located in New Zealand, this privacy statement applies to our activities involving processing personal information wherever in the world we are operating.
In this privacy statement, where we say ‘you’ we mean any individual that we process personal information about.  We will regularly review this privacy statement, and from time to time we may update it. The current version will always be on our website (search for “privacy policy”).
Most of the time, we process personal information to meet our legitimate interests as New Zealand’s national organisation for our grape and wine industry, including making sure we’re providing the best services we can to our members. We may also process personal information to meet our contractual obligations, and at other times will rely on your consent to do so (e.g. for certain marketing purposes).
In this privacy statement you can find out what types of personal information we may collect about you and the particular purposes for which we may use and share it.
To carry out these purposes we may sometimes share personal information with our trusted third-party suppliers who provide us with services such as data storage, webinar hosting, email management, event administration (including payment), auditing and compliance services, and election management.   Where we do so, we do our best to ensure that these third parties will protect your information and only use it for the purposes that we have shared it with them for.  We will never sell your personal information.
In addition to the purposes set out in this privacy statement, we may also collect, use and share your personal information where we are required or allowed to by law (for example, with government agencies), or where you have given your consent.   We may also share personal information about you where we think this is necessary to enforce any legal rights we may have, or to protect the rights, property and/or safety of you or others.
In some circumstances you do not have to provide us with the personal information we ask for.  However please be aware that if you do not provide information we have requested we may not be able to assist you or provide you with services.
What we do with your information
We collect, use and share personal information for the following purposes:
Supporting members
NZW conducts a wide range of tasks to support our members.  To do this we need to collect some personal information about them.  While most of our members are companies (or other legal entities that are not individuals), we do collect and use personal information about the business owner and other people we deal with at those businesses. We are required by law to collect some of this information (for example, under the Wine (Grape Wine) Levy Order, the Commodity Levies (Winegrapes) Order and the Biosecurity (Response - Winegrapes and Grape Wine Levy) Order 2020) in order to be able to administer the levies. Other information is collected for the purpose of communicating with members (including responding to member queries or requests for assistance), providing marketing and promotional services, managing our elections, advocating on behalf of the industry with Government and generally administering memberships.
If you are a participant in the Sustainable Winegrowing New Zealand (SWNZ) programme we will collect information about your sustainability activities (such as water and energy use) and use of agrichemicals, and link this to your NZW membership.  We will use this information to help us to monitor and audit compliance with the programme’s requirements.  To do this we share this information (including name, job title and contact details) with contractors who audit the SWNZ programme on NZW’s behalf.
We may also provide third parties both in New Zealand and overseas with information about which of our members are participating in the SWNZ programme.  If you are also a member of the Sustainability Guardians Programme we may share your contact details with others in the programme to enable collaboration.
We may also share personal information about our members with relevant regional winegrowers associations so that they may make contact with members in their region for the purpose of offering support and providing information.  Similarly, we may share contact information about NZW members with Organic Winegrowers New Zealand Incorporated (OWNZ), so that OWNZ can communicate with its members. We also share member information with New Zealand Winegrowers Research Centre Limited (trading as Bragato Research Institute), a wholly owned subsidiary of NZW, so that it can communicate with members about its work and events.
From time to time we run competitions or surveys that our members can take part in, or offer scholarships or other forms of support to members.  When you provide us with personal information to participate in any of these activities we will use that information solely for the purposes in relation to those activities.
We may also provide you information about opportunities offered by third parties, including scholarships.  In those cases, the third party will be responsible for processing any personal information you share with them for that purpose.
Hosting events
Part of NZW’s role is to provide a global marketing platform for New Zealand wine, including holding events to showcase New Zealand wines.  When we do this, we will collect the personal information we need to administer and run the event (such as the name, contact details and dietary or accessibility requirements of attendees).  Where we take payment for these events we do not collect credit card numbers, as these are managed by the third-party ticketing services we use. We may take and publish photographs or video of event attendees on our website and social media channels.  We will not however use these photographs or video in our print marketing without your prior permission.
If you attend a NZW event we will sometimes ask to share your name and contact details with others (for example, with the wineries who participated in a particular event), and send you relevant information afterwards (unless you tell us not to).
If you are visiting New Zealand as a guest of NZW we will also collect personal information from you in order to plan your itinerary and ensure you have a safe and enjoyable journey in New Zealand.   To facilitate this we may share information about you with relevant third party providers within New Zealand.
Research, marketing and media
So that we can do our job of supporting and promoting New Zealand wine we carry out a range of research and marketing activities, and also publish the New Zealand Winegrower magazine and make media statements where appropriate.  To facilitate these activities, we may collect personal information from you when you interact with us on our website or via social media, work with us on market research (including surveys), participate in an interview, media event or webinar, or when you enter our competitions or promotions.
We may also collect personal information about you when you publicly post or engage with us on social media platforms, participate in stories for our magazine, or make contact us in other ways.  This may include recording your phone calls or other electronic communications with us.
Website visitors
We collect and use information about users of the NZW website so that we can better understand how our website is used.  To do this, we use cookies, which are small data files that our website sends to your browser to be stored on your system for later retrieval by our website.  Cookies track your movements through websites but do not record any personal information about you other than your IP address.  Cookies we use include Google Analytics (and you can find out more about how that works via this link: https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) and Hotjar (https://www.hotjar.com/privacy/). A copy of our full cookie notice is available here.
You can restrict some of the information we collect by changing your cookies and/or browser settings, but this may limit the functionality of the website.
When you log in to the Member Portal we will record the date and time of your access, so that we can help with any log-in issues and manage any security concerns.
Social media cookies
We use social media on some sections of our website to help communicate our messages and give you the best experience – e.g. Facebook and Twitter plugins, and the YouTube videos we embed.
These social media services have their own privacy policies and may track your use of our website on those pages where their links are displayed. They do this by the use of persistent session cookies. If you are logged in to those services (including any Google service) while using our site, their tracking will be associated with your profile with them.
How we look after your personal information
We take care to ensure that the personal information we hold is protected by appropriate security safeguards.  Most of the personal information we store is transferred to and held in New Zealand, which has been granted adequacy status under the General Data Protection Regulation in the European Union.   Where we store personal information in other countries we take steps to ensure this is protected from unauthorised access, misuse and loss by appropriate security safeguards.
We will only retain your personal information for as long as we have a valid basis to do so for the purpose we obtained it, or other lawful purpose.
Your rights
You have the right to request a copy of your personal information, or ask us to correct it if we’ve got it wrong.  In some circumstances, you can withdraw your consent for us to use your personal information, ask us to stop using it, or delete personal information about you.  You may also have the right to be provided a copy of your personal information in an easily portable form.
Members should use the Member Portal to access and update basic personal information NZW holds about them but can still make a request to us for more detailed information that might not be included in the Member Portal.
To exercise any of these rights, or to make a complaint or ask a question about your personal information, please contact us in any of the below ways:
Email advocacy@nzwine.com
Write to NZW, P O Box 90-276, Victoria Street West, Auckland 1142
We’ll do our best to help you, but if we can’t, then you have the right to make a complaint to your local data protection authority about the way we’ve managed your information. You can ask us for help to determine which authority is the right one to contact. In New Zealand, the authority is the Office of the New Zealand Privacy Commissioner who can be contacted by:
completing an online complaint form at privacy.co.nz; or
writing to the Office of the Privacy Commissioner, PO Box 10-094, The Terrace, Wellington 6143.
Copyright
Copyright for all material hosted within the Website is owned by New Zealand Winegrowers Inc unless otherwise indicated. The copyright for material pulled from external platforms is as per specific copyright notices on said platforms.
You may download, store, display, print and reproduce this material in unaltered form only for your personal, non-commercial use or use within your organisation so long as you give appropriate acknowledgement to the copyright owner.
Apart from any use as permitted under the Copyright Act 1994 (NZ), all other rights are reserved.
Requests for further authorisation should be directed to marketing@nzwine.com.
